Statehood Commission
DC Public Library, Special Collections
- Series 9: Correspondence, 1987-1994
  - Correspondence Log, June-August 1994 (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence Log, September 1994 - January 1995 (Box 46, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence statehood, Undated (Box 46, Folder 3)
- Series 10: Articles, 1965-1994
  - "Anatomy of Street Murders" - Follow-up Conference - University of the District of Columbia, September 30-October 1 1988 (Box 46, Folder 4)
  - "Argument Paper for Statehood for D.C." - Ann-Marie Agostinelli, May 2 1988 (Box 46, Folder 5)
  - "The Black American and Bicentennial of the U.S. Constitution: A Mass Media Perspective", 1987 (Box 46, Folder 6)
  - "Briefing Report to Congressional Requester" - D.C. Financial Status - General Accounting Office, June 1994 (Box 46, Folder 7)
  - "The Canal" - Part III [history of the CandO Canal], Undated (Box 46, Folder 8)
  - "Commercial Office Buildings in Washington, 1989 (Box 46, Folder 9)
  - "Congressional Politics and Local Autonomy in Washington, March 13 1989 (Box 46, Folder 10)
  - "Constitutionality of D.C. Statehood” Peter Raven-Hansen - George Washington Law Review, November 1991 (Box 46, Folder 11)
  - "The Council of the District of Columbia", 1987-1988 (Box 46, Folder 12)
  - "The Economic Vitality of the Proposed State of New Columbia: The Federal and Payment; The Commuter Tax Scare: Tourism and "High Tech”, Undated (Box 46, Folder 13)
  - "Federal and Local Interests in the Nation's Capital" - Charles W. Harris, 1994 (Box 46, Folder 14)
  - "The 51st (fifty-first) State: Towards Statehood for the District of Columbia:" Greater Washington Americans for Democratic Action - Clint Hockenberry, October 1984 (Box 46, Folder 15)
  - "Financial Implications of Statehood for D.C." Financial Research Associates, September 1986 (Box 46, Folder 16)
  - "Fiscal Prospects for the State of New Columbia" - Brimmer and Company, September 11 1986 (Box 47, Folder 1)
  - The Five Negro Presidents" - J.A. Rogers, 1965 (Box 47, Folder 2)
  - "The Future of the District of Columbia: Home Rule" - Philip G. Schrag, 1990 (Box 47, Folder 3)
  - "Gut Feelings Toward to the City of Washington and the District of Columbia: Changes Over Time" - Janice H. Hopper (D.C. Statehood Commissioner), Undated (Box 47, Folder 4)
  - "History of Apportionment", Undated (Box 47, Folder 5)
  - "Increased Self-Government for the District of Columbia, December 17 1986 (Box 47, Folder 6)
  - "Human Services in Adams Morgan" - Adams Morgan ANC, Undated (Box 47, Folder 7)
  - If You Favor Freedom - Statehood Commission, October 1986 (Box 47, Folder 8)
  - "In the American Tradition: An Analysis of the Proposed Constitution of the State of New Columbia" - Arnold and Porter, April 1986 (Box 47, Folder 9)
  - Jesse Jackson. We are Campaigning to Build a New Democratic Majority and Rebuild America, November 2 1991 (Box 47, Folder 10)
  - Options in Self-Government for the District of Columbia - Common Cause, 1985 (Box 47, Folder 11)
  - "King and Revolution" - Reflections Vincent Harding, 1983 (Box 47, Folder 12)
  - The New Columbia Times: Special Lobbying Issue, 1992 (Box 47, Folder 13)
  - Eleanor Holmes Norton Newsletter, 1994 (Box 47, Folder 14)
  - "Statehood?" Washington Post Magazine, July 4 1993 (Box 47, Folder 15)
  - "A Qualitative Research Assessment of How Some Americans View the Political Future of the Nation's Capital" - Edward M. Myers, September 1 1994 (Box 47, Folder 16)
  - Republican National Convention calendar, August 14 1998 (Box 47, Folder 17)
  - "Rivlin report: D.C. Shortchanged" - The Washington Post, December 21 1990 (Box 47, Folder 18)
  - "Statehood and Territories" - Congress and the Nation, 1960s (Box 47, Folder 19)
  - Statehood bibliography, Undated (Box 47, Folder 20)
  - Statehood Call: Voice of the Statehood Party, March 13 1971 (Box 47, Folder 21)
  - Statehood Call: Voice of the Statehood Party, March 22 1981 (Box 47, Folder 22)
  - "Statehood for the District of Columbia" - National Academy for Public Administration, 1990 (Box 47, Folder 23)
  - "Statehood for New Columbia" - edited by James Forman, 1993 (Box 47, Folder 24)
  - State Government [various articles on government organization], 1979, 1985-1986 (Box 47, Folder 25)
  - The Statehood Papers: Articles on D.C. Statehood by Sam Smith - published by Progressive Review, 1970-1991 (Box 47, Folder 26)
  - Statehood quotes, Undated (Box 48, Folder 1)
  - Statistics of Income Bulletin, 1988 (Box 48, Folder 2)
  - "The Struggle for Self-Determination in the District of Columbia: A Celebration of the Life Activities of the Honorable" - Julius Hobson, Josephine Butler and Bill O'Field, Undated (Box 48, Folder 3)
  - The Utility Bulletin - D.C. Public Utilities Commission, 1989 (Box 48, Folder 4)
  - "Before Watergate: Problems of Corruption in American Society" - Abraham S. Eisenstadt et al., 1978 (Box 48, Folder 5)
  - The Williamsburg Charter, June 25 1988 (Box 48, Folder 6)
- Series 11: Articles, 1965-1994
  - 200 Years of History in Cleveland Park, Undated (Box 48, Folder 7)
  - Camera, Undated (Box 48, Folder 8)
  - Centennial Celebration Western-Ellington, 1990 (Box 48, Folder 9)
  - Citizens for New Columbia - promotional items, Undated (Box 48, Folder 10)
  - D.C. Statehood Commission folder, Undated (Box 48, Folder 11)
  - D.C. Statehood Commission stationary, Undated (Box 48, Folder 12)
  - "D.C. Statehood Now" button, Undated (Box 48, Folder 13)
  - D.C. Statehood tote bag, Undated (Box 48, Folder 14)
  - Duke Ellington School of the Arts - Annual Spring Dance Concert program, May 25-26 1990 (Box 48, Folder 15)
  - "The Facts About D.C. Statehood", Undated (Box 48, Folder 16)
  - Flag for New Columbia story, Undated (Box 48, Folder 17)
  - "Jobs, Undated (Box 48, Folder 18)
  - March for D.C. Statehood flyers, January 1991 (Box 48, Folder 19)
  - Charles Noble Mason - "An Evening of Appreciation", April 9 1988 (Box 48, Folder 20)
  - "Mend the Crack in the Liberty Bell; D.C. Statehood Now!" bumper sticker, Undated (Box 48, Folder 21)
  - Peace Train flyer, Undated (Box 48, Folder 22)
  - Poems and songs, Undated (Box 48, Folder 23)
  - "Progressive Alternative in District Politics" [Statehood Party brochures], Undated (Box 48, Folder 24)
  - Singham Memorial tribute, 1991 (Box 48, Folder 25)
  - "Socialist for President Margaret Wright 1976-The People's Party" bumper sticker (Box 48, Folder 26)
  - Statehood Coalition poster, Undated (Box 48, Folder 27)
  - Statehood Coalition - "D.C. Statehood Now!" brochure, Undated (Box 48, Folder 28)
  - Statehood petition [blank], Undated (Box 48, Folder 29)
  - "The Struggle for Self-Determination: From D.C. to El Salvador" flyer, Undated (Box 48, Folder 30)
  - "Support D.C. Statehood" bumper sticker, Undated (Box 48, Folder 31)
  - Vote for D.C. State Constitution, Undated (Box 48, Folder 32)
  - "Welcome to Washington: The Last Colony" flyer, 1988 (Box 48, Folder 33)
- Series 12: Jo Butler Materials, 1978-1993
  - Adams Morgan/Lanier Heights Historical Research Survey, 1982-1987 (Box 49, Folder 1)
  - Biography, Undated (Box 49, Folder 2)
  - Birthday cards, Undated (Box 49, Folder 3)
  - Campaign Finance Office, 1984 (Box 49, Folder 4)
  - Campaign Poster, Undated (Box 49, Folder 5)
  - Candidate petition, Undated (Box 49, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1978-1984 (Box 49, Folder 7)
  - Hansib Community Award, 1989 (Box 49, Folder 8)
  - Resignation, 1993 (Box 49, Folder 9)
  - Resignation from ANC, 1987 (Box 49, Folder 10)
  - Resumes, Undated (Box 49, Folder 11)
  - Working Files, 1988-1991 (Box 49, Folder 12)
  - Working Files, 1988-1991 (Box 49, Folder 13)
  - Working Files, 1988-1991 (Box 49, Folder 14)
  - Working Files, 1988-1991 (Box 49, Folder 15)
  - Working Files, 1988-1991 (Box 49, Folder 16)
- Series 13: Audiovisual, 1986-1994
  - Audiotapes of Statehood/Compact Commission Meeting, September 19 1986 - May 5 1988 (Box 50, Folder 1)
  - Audiotapes of Statehood/Compact Commission Meeting, May 5 1988 - December 15 1988 (Box 51, Folder 1)
  - Videotape - Joia Jefferson "In the Public Eye: D.C. Statehood", July 26 1994 (Box 51, Folder 2)
  - Joia Jefferson - "In the Public Eye: D.C. Statehood", July 26 1994 (Box 51, Folder 3)
  - Statehood Now Demonstration photo, Undated (Box 51, Folder 4)
  - Unidentified photo (related to Adams Morgan Lanier Heights Survey), Undated (Box 51, Folder 5)
  - Calendar, 1989 (Box 51, Folder 6)
  - Statehood Now Posters, Undated (Box 51, Folder 7)